Finding Aid for William Muschenheim papers 1923-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs and Accompanying Material
  - Miscellaneous
    - Color Slides, Boxed: "Roosevelt Competition, Phi Epsilon Pi, Huron Valley Presentation, Expo, Miscellaneous" (Box 11)
    - Color Slides, Boxed: "Form, Color" (Box 11)
  - Murphy, William J. House (#80) (Box 11)
  - Muschenheim, William, Heatherway House (#132), 4 folders (Box 11)
  - New School for Social Research (Box 11)
  - New York World's Fair, Marine Transportation Pavilion (#51) (Box 11)
  - Paul, Ara (#184), slides, color prints (Box 11)
  - Phi Epsilon Pi (#146) (Box 11)
  - Plischke (Box 11)
  - Rutledge, Don House (#135) (Box 11)
  - School Projects
    - Apartment Hotel (Box 11)
    - Country Club (Box 11)
    - House on Dunes (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Restaurant on Dunes (Box 11)
  - Slum Clearance Project (#41) (Box 11)
  - Unidentified Prints, Slides, Negatives (Box 11)
  - University of Michigan Art Museum (#136) (Box 11)
  - Von Rebay Barn (#59) (Box 11)
  - "Wieselthier" (Box 11)
  - William Muschenheim Apartment (#5) (Box 11)
  - Wilkes, Felix Mrs. Apartment (#7) (Box 11)
  - Astor Hotel (#39) (Box 12)
  - Bath Houses (Box 12)
  - De Liagre, Alfred House (#43) (Box 12)
  - Hampton Bay House Exterior (#3) (Box 12)
  - Hampton Bay House Interior (#3) (Box 12)
  - Picnic Car (Box 12)
- Presentation Boards
  The Presentation Boards (1.75 linear feet. and 1 flat drawer), which are mainly black and white photographs and groupings of photographs, an effective and efficient way to review the scope of Muschenheim's career through the early 1960s. Work he selected as representative and significant include the Bath Houses on the Dunes; Astor Hotel Projects; the Dance Laboratory at the New School for Social Research; the Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum; the Marine Transportation Building at the 1939 New York World's Fair; the Museum of Art Main Stair and Exhibition Space, University of Michigan; and the Rutledge and Harrison Houses.
  - Samples of Work, 17 boards
    - Bath Houses on the Dunes 1930 (Box 12)
    - Gulden Penthouse, #27 1933 (Box 12)
    - Dance Laboratory, New School for Social Research 1933 (Box 12)
    - Astor Cafe, #39 1934 (Box 12)
    - Ball Room Lobby and Coat Room, #39 1935 (Box 12)
    - De Liagre House 1937 (#43) (Box 12)
    - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, #60 1939 (Box 12)
    - Marine Transportation Bldg., New York World's Fair 1939 (#51) (Box 12)
    - Hard House, #79 1941 (Box 12)
    - Murphy House, #80 1950 (Box 12)
    - Muschenheim Houses, Hampton Bays, #3 and #31 1925-1936 (Box 12)
    - Muschenheim House, Ann Arbor, #132 1954 (Box 12)
    - Museum of Art, University of Michigan, #136 1957 (Box 12)
    - Rutledge House, #135,1960 (Box 12)
    - Harrison House, #133 1961 (Box 12)
  - Slum Clearing House Proposal, #41, 3 boards (Box 12)
  - Marine Transportation Bldg., New York World's Fair 1939 (#51) (Box 13)
  - Model, House on Dunes 1927 (#3), 6 boards (Box 13)
  - Set 1
    - Bath Houses, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1930, 2 boards (Map-case 7)
    - Rutledge Residence, Ann Arbor,1961, 3 boards (Map-case 7)
    - Museums Remodeling 1939, 1947, 1957, 2 boards (Map-case 7)
  - Set 2
    - Additions to House, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1925-1930 (Map-case 7)
    - Miscellaneous Interiors, New York, N.Y. 1930-1936 (Map-case 7)
    - Lobby Leading to Restaurants and Roof Garden Alterations, Hotel Astor 1932-1938 (Map-case 7)
    - Banquet Hall Cafe and Ball Room Alterations, Hotel Astor 1934-1938 (Map-case 7)
    - Coat Room, Bar, Roof Restaurant, Hotel Astor 1934-1935 (Map-case 7)
    - Alteration to Cottage, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1934, 2 boards (Map-case 7)
    - House, Woodstock, N.Y. 1937 (Map-case 7)
    - $7000 Summer Cottage, Nassau Point, L.I.,1941 (Map-case 7)
    - Addition to House, Remsenburg, L.I. 1949 (Map-case 7)
    - House, Ann Arbor, Michigan 1954, 3 boards (Map-case 7)
    - Unistrut Platforms and Display Frames, University Museum, Ann Arbor, Michigan 1957 and S.R. Guggenheim Museum, 1939, 2 boards (Map-case 7)
  - Guggenheim Museum (#60, #102) (Map-case 7)
  - Gulden, Immo Apartment and House (#27) (Map-case 7)
  - Hampton Bays
    - Bath Houses on Dunes (Map-case 7)
    - Dr. Carl Muschenheim House (#31) (Map-case 7)
    - F.A. Muschenheim House Exterior (#3) (Map-case 7)
    - F.A. Muschenheim House Interior (#3) (Map-case 7)
    - Lighthouse (Map-case 7)
  - Hard House (#79) (Map-case 7)
  - Harlem Housing (Map-case 7)
  - Harrison, Burton House (#133), mainly color prints (Map-case 7)
  - Hawkes, A. W. House (#83) (Map-case 7)
  - Hermannson, Hermann (#186), color prints (Map-case 7)
  - International Congress of Modern Architecture, Baltimore Map (Map-case 7)
  - Mason, Terry Apartment (#111) (Map-case 7)
  - McPherson, Ross Dr. Office (#36) (Map-case 7)
  - M.I.T. Museum Project (Map-case 7)
- Original Drawings and Prints
  The Original Drawings and Prints series consists of oversize sketches, renderings and drawings that complement the documentation of individual project listed in the Projects Files series, or in some cases may constitute the only documentation of a project. The series occupies six flat drawers and is arranged by project number.
  - #112 Anita Zahn: Alteration to Summer School of the Arts, East Hampton, Long Island, New York, 1948.
    - One sketch, black ink on tracing paper (Map-case 1)
  - #113 William Murphy: House, 1 folders
    - Rendering undated, watercolor on blueline mounted on board (Map-case 1)
  - #132 William Muschenheim: House, 10 folders
    - Sketches undated, pencil and orange pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 1)
    - Preliminary Drawings 1952, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 1)
    - Renderings undated, black ink on tracing paper (Map-case 1)
    - Topographical, 1952-1953, pencil and colored pencil on bluelines (Map-case 1)
    - Design Development Drawings and Sketches undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper; black ink on tracing paper (Map-case 1)
    - Color Studies undated, watercolor and ink on blueline prints; colored pencil on blueline; pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper; colored pencil, marker and paint on bluelines (Map-case 1)
    - Original Working Drawings, 1-23 and 24-36 1953-1988, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper and vellum (Map-case 1)
    - Original Drawings and Prints: Details 1954-1984, undated, pencil and red pencil on vellum, tracing paper and graph paper; red ink on Xerox prints; blueline; blueprint (Map-case 1)
    - Prints: Electrical, Heating, Framing, yellow and red pencil on blueprints and bluelines (Map-case 1)
    - Prints: Structural, bluelines (Map-case 1)
  - #133 Burton Harrison: Alterations to Residence and Additions, 5 folders
    - Plans by T. Stanner, Architect undated, blueprints (Map-case 2)
    - Design Development Sketches and Drawings 1966, undated, blue ink and pencil on tracing paper; pencil on blueprints and bluelines; sepia print (Map-case 2)
    - Original Working Drawings, 1-19, 35, 39-40, 51-54 1955-1982, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper; pencil on vellum (Map-case 2)
    - Color Studies undated, colored pencil on tracing paper and bluelines; cut paper on bluelines; cut paper, blue marker, pencil and paint on bluelines (Map-case 2)
    - Miscellaneous Prints, blueline; red pencil on bluelines; blueprint (Map-case 2)
  - #134 Martin Bernstein: Alterations to Residence, 1 folders
    - Mixed Drawings and Prints 1955, pencil on tracing paper; watercolor, cut paper, blue marker on bluelines (Map-case 2)
  - #135 Don. H. Rutledge: House, 5 folders
    - Sketches, Site Plan 1956, undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper and blueline (Map-case 2)
    - Preliminary Plans, Elevations, Plot Plans, Isometrics, Axiomatic, Floor Plan, Section 1956-1959, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper and bluelines; black ink on tracing paper (Map-case 2)
    - Color Studies and Details undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper and bluelines; black ink on tracing paper (Map-case 2)
    - Original Working Drawings, 1-22 1957-1969, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper; pencil on vellum (Map-case 2)
    - Miscellaneous Prints 1957-1959, undated, colored pencil on bluelines (Map-case 2)
  - #136 Museum of Art, University of Michigan: Main Stair, Platforms and Exhibition Space, 3 folders
    - Mixed Drawings Including Original Studies and Working Drawings 1957, undated, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 3)
    - Color Studies and Presentation Boards 1957, undated, colored pencil, cut paper, collage on tracing paper and bluelines (Map-case 3)
    - Mixed Prints 1954-1957, bluelines, red pencil on bluelines (Map-case 3)
  - #138 Ankars International Competition, Middle East Technical University: Building for School of Administrative Sciences, 2 folders; 2 boards
    - Original Drawings and Sketches undated, pencil, colored pencil and colored marker on tracing paper (Map-case 3)
    - Mixed Prints, bluelines, blacklines and colored pencil on bluelines (Map-case 3)
    - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case 3)
  - #139 F.D.R. Memorial Competition, 2 folders; 2 boards
    - Original Sketches and Drawings undated (Map-case 3)
    - Mixed Prints undated (Map-case 3)
    - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case 3)
  - #146 Phi Epsilon Pi Fraternity House, 9 folders
    - Topological Surveys 1962-1966, bluelines (Map-case 4)
    - Mixed Original Drawings 1962-1967, undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper; pencil on graph paper (Map-case 4)
    - Original Site Plan, Floor Plan, Section, Plot Plan undated, black ink on tracing paper (Map-case 4)
    - Original Working Drawings, A-F and 1-15 1962, 1966, pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 4)
    - Original Drawings: Details and Electrical, E Series-5B 1962, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 4)
    - Color Studies undated, colored pencil on bluelines (Map-case 4)
    - Furniture Layout Studies undated, pencil and blue marker on tracing paper; pencil and orange marker on bluelines; colored marker on tracing paper (Map-case 4)
    - Mixed Prints, including Electrical and Heating 1962-1965, orange marker on bluelines (Map-case 4)
    - Prints, "Set 33" 1965, bluelines (Map-case 4)
    - Prints, "Set 42" Office Copy, bluelines (Map-case 4)
  - #157 Mr. and Mrs. Ned Flanders: Residence, 1 folders (Map-case 5)
    - Original Drawings 1968, marker and pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 5)
  - #160 Blue Cross, Blue Shield Detroit, 1 folders
    - Prints, bluelines (Map-case 5)
  - #162 International Organization Headquarters and Conference Center, Vienna, Austria: International Competition, 3 folders
    - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case 5)
    - Original Drawings undated, cut paper and ink on vellum; pencil on tracing paper and vellum; black ink on vellum (Map-case 5)
      (includes "Exploding Tower Diagram")
    - Mixed Prints with Color, colored pencil, marker and ink on bluelines (Map-case 5)
  - #163 Robert Knaus: Weekend House, 2 folders
    - Mixed Original Sketches and Drawings undated, colored marker on tracing paper and vellum; pencil on tracing paper and vellum (Map-case 5)
    - Mixed Prints, bluelines (Map-case 5)
  - #170 Mr. Lyne: Alterations to Residence, 1 folders
    - Mixed Original Drawings and Print 1969, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper; blueline (Map-case 5)
  - #172 Joseph T.A. Lee: Market Arbor "A" Center, 1 folders
    - Mixed Original Drawings, Prints and Presentation Board,1970 and undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper and vellum; colored marker on blueline (Map-case 5)
  - #183 Dr. Helen Gay: Additions to House, 1976, 1 folders (Map-case 5)
  - #184 Ara G. Paul: Additions and Alterations to House, 3 folders
    - Design Development, Studies undated, colored pencil and cut paper on tracing paper and Xerox prints (Map-case 5)
    - Original Working Drawings 1988, pencil and red pencil on vellum; pencil on tracing paper (Map-case 5)
    - Prints (Photocopy prints) (Map-case 5)
  - #186 Hermann Hermannsson: House, 2 folders
    - Original Sketches and Drawings 1980-1986, pencil and yellow pencil on vellum and tracing paper (Map-case 6)
    - Prints 1954-1984, bluelines (Map-case 6)
  - #187 Silas Woods: House, 1 folders
    - Original Working Drawings 1981-1982, pencil on vellum (Map-case 6)
  - #192 Astronaut's Memorial, 2 folders
    - Original Drawings and Sketches undated, pencil on tracing paper and vellum; black marker on tracing paper; colored pencil and black marker on vellum (Map-case 6)
    - Mixed Prints (Map-case 6)
  - Unnumbered
    - East Hampton Air Terminal, 2 folders
      - Original Drawings undated, pencil on vellum; ink and pencil on mylar (Map-case 6)
      - Color Studies undated, colored pencil on Xerox prints; cut paper on Xerox prints (Map-case 6)
      - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case 6)
    - Washington State Veteran's Memorial Competition undated, 1 folders collage on blueline (Map-case 6)
    - International Competition for the selection of architects for the Middle East Technical University, Ankara, Turkey undated, 1 folders (Map-case 6)
  - Unidentified; Miscellaneous (Map-case 6)
- Digitization Project
  The series (1 linear foot) contains materials from a collaborative project between the Bentley and Columbia University's Avery Library undertaken from approximately 2002 to 2004, in which slides, photographs, and drawings were scanned, and made accessible online though an integrated finding aid. The series includes project documentation such as correspondence, logs, and notes; slides; negatives; and approximately 185 CDs containing scans of master TIFF files which can be found online.
  - 2002-2004, undated, 3 folders; 6 boxes; 2 boxes (Box 12)
Muschenheim Project Collocation List
The following list provides a composite listing of materials at the Bentley Historical Library related to an individual project that may be filed in multiple series because of format, size or Muschenheim's arrangement of the materials. Researchers should note that the Avery Library, Columbia University, holds Muschenheim records and drawings representing the early part of his career -- work numbered 1 to 131. The Bentley collection, except for the Photograph Series, mainly documents work numbered between 132 and 192. A list of projects prepared and dated by Muschenheim is attached to this finding aid. See the combined finding aid title Muschenheim, William. Architectural drawings and papers for a complete listing of Bentley and Avery Library holdings
#112 -- Anita Zahn
Drawer 1
#113 -- Wm. J. Murphy, Alteration and Addition to Summer Residence
Drawer 7
#132 -- Wm. Muschenheim: House
Work File, Box 7
Photographs, Boxes 11, 12
Drawings, Drawer 1, 7
#133 -- Burton Harrison: Alteration to Residence and Additions
Work File, Box 7
Photographs, Box 11, Box 12
Drawings, Drawer 2, 7
#134 -- Prof. Martin Bernstein: Alteration to Residence
Work File, Box 7
Drawings, Drawer 2
#135 -- Rutledge, Don H.: House
Work File, Box 7
Photographs, Box 11, Box 12
Drawings, Drawer 3
#136 -- Museum of Art, University of Michigan; Main Stair, Platforms and Exhibition Space
Work File, Box 8
Photographs, Box 11, Box 12
Drawings, Drawer 3, 7
#137 -- G. Bruce McCaleb: Alterations to Residence
Work File, Box 8
#138 -- Ankars International Competition; Middle East Technical University: Building for School of Administrative Sciences
Work File, Box 8
Photographs, Box 10
Drawings, Drawer 3
#139 -- FDR Memorial Competition: Memorial in Washington
Work File, Box 8
Photographs, Box 10
Drawings, Drawer 3
Presentation Boards, Drawer 3
#140 -- Joseph Blatt: Alterations to Residence
Work File, Box 8
#141 -- Harry Lieberman: Designs for Development Houses
Work File, Box 8
#142 -- Rackham Grant, University of Michigan / Color Plates
Publications and Research, Boxes 5 and 6
#143 -- A. Benjamin Handler: Alterations to Residence
Work File, Box 8
#144 -- A.I.A. [American Institute of Architects]
Biographical and Professional, Box 1
#145-- Robert E. Schwartz: Consultations - Church, Shopping Center
Work File, Box 8
#146 -- Phi Epsilon Pi Fraternity House: Alterations and Annex
Work File, Box 8
Photographs, Box 11
Drawings, Drawer 4
#147 -- Claude A. Eggerstein: Addition to Residence
Work File, Box 8
#148 -- Rackham Grant: 1964 Sabbatical Trip
Publications and Research, Box 4
#149 -- Richard Stoll: Consultation re: Residence
Work File, Box 8
#150 -- Alpha Ki Delta Sorority: Consultations re: Building
Work File, Box 8
#151 -- NCARB: Foreign Evaluation Committee
Work File, Box 1
#152 -- Sleepy Hollow Cemetery
Work File, Box 8
#153 -- Emile Voelcker: Addition to Residence
Work File, Box 8
#157 -- Flanders Residence
Drawings, Drawer 5
#160 -- Blue Cross, Blue Shield, Detroit
Drawings, Drawer 5
#162 -- International Organization Headquarters & Conference Center, Vienna, Austria: International Competition
Work File, Box 8
Photographs, Box 10
Drawings, Drawer 5
#163 -- Mr. and Mrs. Robert Knauss: Week-End House
Work File, Box 8
Drawings, Drawer 5
#169 -- Mr. Sabaliunas: Alterations to Residence
Work File, Box 8
#170 -- Mr. Lyne
Drawings, Drawer 5
#172 -- Mr. Jos. T.A. Lee: Market Arbor "A" Center
Work File, Box 9
Drawings, Drawer 5
#175 -- Correspondence: Book
Publications and Research, Box 4
#176 -- Rockresorts: Lobby and Board Room
Work File, Box 9
#177 -- Mr. Channing Jacques: Addition to Cottage
Work File, Box 9
#178 -- Mr. A.B. Handler: Addition to House
Work File, Box 9
#181 -- City of Grand Rapids Museum: re Alterations to Old Federal Building
Work File, Box 9
#183 -- Dr. Helen Gay: Addition to House
Work File, Box 9
Drawings, Drawer 5
#184 -- Mr. Ara G. Paul: Addition and Alterations to House
Work File, Box 9
Drawings, Drawer 5
Photographs, Box 11
#185 -- Karoma Publishers: Book, Why Architecture
Publications and Research, Box 4
#186 -- Mr. Hermann Hermannsson: New House
Work File, Box 9
Photographs, Box 10
Drawings, Drawer 6
#187 Mr. Silas Woods: New House
Work File, Box 9
Drawings, Drawer 6
#188 -- Mr. J.E. Keith Smith: Railing and Approach to Restaurant
Work File, Box 9
#189 -- Mr. Peter Meister: Alteration to Residence
Work File, Box 9
#190 -- Robert Cole: Consultation
Work File, Box 9
#191 -- Mr. and Mrs. Dozauer: Residence Alterations
Work File, Box 9
Drawings, Drawer 6
#192 -- Astronaut's Memorial
Drawer 6
Unnumbered:
East Hampton Air Terminal Competition
Drawings, Drawer 6
Washington State Memorial Competition
Drawings, Drawer 6
Unidentified; Miscellaneous
Drawings: Drawer 6
Work File: Box 9
Photographs: Box 11
List of William Muschenheim Work
Project No. Owner/Client Location Date
1. Architectural Registration (See General File) 1934
2. Curtis Allen, Chestnut Hill, PA New House, Chestnut Hill, PA 1929
3. F.A. Muschenheim, 218 West 45th Street, N.Y.C. Playhouse and Bathhouse, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1925-30
4. John A. Dunbar, 50 East 77th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 50 East 77th Street, N.Y.C. 1930
5. William Muschenheim, 1 Lexington Ave., N.Y.C. Alterations to Apartments, New York City 1930-49
6. Strauss Memorial Committee, New York City Memorial, Central Park West, N.Y.C. 1930
7. Mrs. Felix Wilckes, 136 East 64th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment & Penthouse Alt., New York City 1930-31
8. Marshall Unit Steel Framing, New York City Week-end House(?) 1932
9. Architectural League, 215 West 57th Street, N.Y.C. Penthouse Competition (Exhibition) 1932
10. Schulte Cigar Company,New York City. Webster Cigar Adv. & Store, Front Alterations, N.Y.C. 1931
11.-17. (Skipped numbers -- continued with 18)
18. ? Design of $1000.00 House, Long Island, N.Y.
19. Douglas Elliman Modernization of Apt. "A" & "B" 1938
20. Mrs. Eleanor Labrot, 326 East 51st Street, N.Y.C. House Alteration, 326 East 51st Street, N.Y.C.
21. Urban's Theatre, Westchester, N.Y. Design 1938
22. Mrs. Neil Finch, 125 East 72nd Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 125 East 72nd Street, N.Y.C. 1938
23. (skipped -- See 24.)
24. Mrs. T.W. Page (Misc. Consultations) 1936-38
25- 26. (skipped -- See 27.)
27a. Immo Gulden, Rumson, N.J. Penthouse, 530 East 86th Street, N.Y.C. 1933
27b. Game Room, Rumson, N.J.
28-29. (skipped -- continue with 30.)
30. Mrs. H.J. Koehler, Hotel Astor, Times Square, N.Y.C. Refurnishing Hotel apartment, Hotel Astor, N.Y.C. 1934
31. Dr. Carl Muschenheim, 1327 Lexington Avenue, N.Y.C. House Alteration, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1934
32. Walter D. Fletcher, 520 East 86th Street, N.Y.C. New House, Hampton Bays, L.I., Apartment Alteration, N.Y.C. 1934
33. General Electric Company, 51st St., & Lexington Ave., N.Y.C. (Small House Competition) 1934
34. Hoegger, Inc., Weehawken, N.J. (Design for Chairs) 1934
35. Paul Scholze, Huntington, L.I. New House, Melville, Huntington, L.I. 1935
36. Dr. Ross McPherson, 842 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. Office Alt., 842 Park Ave., N.Y., Apartment Alt., N.Y.C. 1934
37. E. Voelker, 205 East 78th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 205 East 78th Street, N.Y.C. 1935
38. Robert G. Stewart, 447 East 57th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 447 East 57th Street, N.Y.C. 1935
39. Hotel Astor, Times Square, N.Y.C. Alterations to Belvedere 1935
40. N.Y.S. Department of Health, Albany, New York Consultation (Furnishing Community Room, Albany) 1935
41. N.Y.C. Housing Authority, 122 East 42nd Street, N.Y.C., District No. 5 -- Manhattan Slum Clearance 1935
42. Portland Comment Assn. 347 Madison Avenue, N.Y.C. (Small House Competition) 1935
43. Alfred DeLiagre, 74 Trinity Place, N.Y.C. New House, Woodstock, N.Y. 1936
44. Starrett Bros., & Eken, 40 Wall Street, N.Y.C. Apartment House Development, East 90th Street, N.Y.C. 1936
45. A. Lawrence Kocher Articles (Modern Architecture) 1936
Archt. Record - 119 W. 40th St., N.Y.C.
46. N.Y.C.O.S. -- (See job #53)
47. New York World's Fair, Flushing, L.I. (Competition) 1936-37
48. Bliss, Fabyan & Co., 32 Thomas Street, N.Y.C. Store Front Alteration, 32 Thomas Street, N.Y.C. 1937
49. Herbert W. Forster, 195 Broadway, N.Y.C. House Alteration, Rockville Center, L.I. 1939
50. Wm. B.F. Drew, 570 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. Alterations to Apartments, 570 Park Ave., & E. 64th St., N.Y. 1941
51. New York World's Fair (1939), Flushing, L.I. Marine Transportation Building 1938
52. Walter D. Fletcher, 520 East 86th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 520 East 86th Street, N.Y.C. 1937
53. Alfred Barush, 30 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y.C. Cooperative Development, Long Island, N.Y. 1933
54. Franklin B. Kirkbride, 74 Trinity Place N.Y.C. Miscellaneous Alteration Work, New Canaan, Conn. 1939-46
55. Architectural League of New York, 115 East 40th Street, N.Y.C. (Exhibit) 1938
56. Wheaton College, Massachusetts (Art Center Competition) 1938
57. Random House, Inc. 20 East 57th Street, N.Y.C. (Book Cover Design) 1938
58. Countess Mara, Inc., 338 Park Ave., N.Y.C. Men's Shop, 338 Park Ave., N.Y.C. 1938
58a. Mrs. M.D. Whitman, 320 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 320 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. 1938
59. Baroness Hills von Rebay, Westport, Conn. Alteration to Barn, Westport, Conn. 1938
60. Guggenheim Foundation, 24 East 54th Street, N.Y.C. Museum for Non-objective Art 1939
61. Thomas S. Holden, Barien, Conn. House Alteration, Barien, Conn. 1939
62. Smithsonian Institute, Washington, D.C. (Gallery of Art Competition) 1939
63. Miss Annette Reilly (W.B.F. Drew) Apartment Alteration 1939
64. Dr. Kurt Shelling, 240 East 79th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 240 East 79th Street, N.Y.C. 1939
65. A.W. Bianchi, 320 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 320 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. 1939
66. Ramsen Community Corporation, Brooklyn, N.Y. House Alteration, 58 Ramsen Street, Brooklyn, N.Y. 1940
67. Beaux Arts Institute of Design, 304 East 44th Street, N.Y.C. (Student Program) 1939
68. Mrs. Arthur Bodansky, 140 East 28th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 140 East 28th Street, N.Y.C. 1939-49
69. Mrs. Linda Fletcher, 230 East 73rd Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 230 East 73rd Street, N.Y.C. 1940